Arise for Social Justice Records, 1956-2010 (bulk 1985-2010)
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES XXIII. VIOLENCE, [see also SERIES IV. CRIMINAL JUSTICE and SERIES III. CHILDREN AND YOUTH]
  - Arise Violence Against Women Committee
    - General 1992-2003 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Event: "Framingham Eight" screening and talk by Lisa Grimshaw 21 Jun 1994 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - March for Zero Tolerance/Take Back the Night 1993-2006 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Media Roundtable 4 Feb 1994 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Media Responsibility Training 3 Feb 1995 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Petition re: media treatment of victims undated (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Membership Conference "Working to End Violence Against Women" (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Support Group undated (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Vigils for victims of violence
      - General 1993-98, undated (Box 26, Folder 25)
      - Jennifer Davile 1993-94 (Box 26, Folder 26)
      - Elizabeth Delgado 1993 (Box 26, Folder 27)
      - Lisa Dolley 1993 (Box 26, Folder 28)
      - Robin Jackson undated (Box 26, Folder 29)
      - Kelly Richard 1993 (Box 26, Folder 30)
      - Victoria Sleeper 1993 (Box 26, Folder 31)
      - Marvina "Tasha" Stroman 1994 (Box 26, Folder 32)
      - Miriam "Vicky" Tyson 1993-94 (Box 26, Folder 33)
      - Lisa Ziegert 1992, undated (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Women's Self-Defense Classes/Workshops, Valley Women's Martial Arts 1985-98, undated (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - Organizations and resources
    - General 1986-97, undated (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Battered and Homeless Shelter Linkage Project 1993, undated (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - Baystate Medical Center Domestic Violence Working Group 1994-95 (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - Hotline to End Rape and Abuse (HERA) 1982-87, undated (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - Massachusetts Coalition of Battered Women's Service Groups 1993-95, undated (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - Women's Action Coalition undated (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - YWCA of Western Massachusetts/ARCH (Abuse and Rape Crisis Hotline) 1992-94 (Box 26, Folder 42)
  - Reference files
    - General 1986-98 (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - Domestic violence (includes children, partners, & elderly) 1992-96 (Box 26, Folder 44)
    - Fact sheets 1992-97, undated (Box 26, Folder 45)
    - Laws 1995, undated (Box 26, Folder 46)
    - Shelters 1990-94, undated (Box 26, Folder 47)
    - Springfield 1994-98 (Box 26, Folder 48)
    - Violence Against Women-General
      - General 1991-95, undated (Box 26, Folder 49)
      - Rape/sexual assault 1978-93, undated (Box 26, Folder 50)
      - Welfare 1995-97, undated (Box 26, Folder 51)
- SERIES XXIV. WELFARE, [see also SERIES XI. HOMELESSNESS, SERIES XII. HOUSING, and SERIES XVIII. POVERTY/ECONOMIC JUSTICE]
  - Arise
    - General 1985-99, undated (Box 26, Folder 52)
    - Welfare/Welfare Issues Committee 1989-94, undated (Box 26, Folder 53)
    - Demonstrations, marches, rallies, vigils
      - General 1986-99, undated (Box 26, Folder 54-55)
      - Ways and Means Committee testimony 10 May 1989 (Box 26, Folder 56)
      - Speak Out, Dorchester 26 Sep 1998 (Box 26, Folder 57)
    - Pell Grants and Food Stamp eligibility
      - General 1984-86, undated (Box 26, Folder 58-59)
      - Low-Income Students for Survival 1986, undated (Box 26, Folder 60)
    - Petitions re EA, GR, Children's Clothing Allowance and 707 cuts undated (Box 26, Folder 61)
    - Welfare Advocacy Training 30 Nov 1990 (Box 26, Folder 62)
    - Welfare workshop 20 Aug 1997 (Box 26, Folder 63)
  - Clippings 1985-99, undated (Box 26, Folder 64-65)
  - Conferences and workshops
    - Miscellaneous 1993-95, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - "Survival in the 80s" workshop 1985 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Northeastern Regional Welfare Rights Conference 1993 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - "Welfare Reform and the Faith Community," [original title "Standing With the Poor"] interfaith seminar 19 Oct 1995 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - "Revisiting, Redefining and Revisioning 'Welfare'," Kathleen Ridder Conference, Smith College 1998 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - "Get Up, Stand Up," Bertha Capen Reynolds Society National Conference 1999 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Fact sheets
    - General 1985-99, undated (Box 27, Folder 7-8)
    - Coalition for Basic Human Needs undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Re: legislation 1988-97, undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - "Survival Tips" undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Your Rights Under Welfare Reform, Massachusetts Law Reform Institute 1995, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Organizations
    - Center for Community Change 1997-2000, undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Center on Social Welfare Policy and Law 1983-85 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Coalition for Basic Human Needs (CBHN) 1985-96, undated (Box 27, Folder 15-17)
    - Connecticut Alliance for Basic Human Needs 1993-98, undated (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Dottie Stevens for Governor 1990-91 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Family Economic Initiative 1997-2001, undated (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Human Service Forum 1988-93 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Institute for Women's Policy Research 1994, undated (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Kensington Welfare Rights Union undated (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Labor and Welfare Coalition: Legislative Fact Sheets circa 1997 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Massachusetts, Commonwealth of
      - General 1985-98, undated (Box 27, Folder 25-26)
      - Welfare Discussion Group 1990-91 (Box 27, Folder 27)
      - Department of Public Welfare (DPW)
        - General 1985-94, undated (Box 27, Folder 28-30)
        - Budget hearings 1985 (Box 27, Folder 31)
        - Employment and Training (ET) Program undated (Box 27, Folder 32)
        - "Guide for Advisory Boards" undated (Box 27, Folder 33)
        - Springfield Community Service Area Welfare Advisory Board
          - By-laws undated (Box 27, Folder 34)
          - General 1985-88 (Box 27, Folder 35-37)
        - Welfare application and information 1985, undated (Box 27, Folder 38)
      - Department of Transitional Assistance (DTA) 1995-98, undated (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Massachusetts Human Services Coalition
      - General 1989-96, undated (Box 27, Folder 40)
      - Campaign for Real Welfare Reform 1992-95, undated (Box 27, Folder 41)
      - Women's Campaign for Social Justice 1987-89, [see also SERIES XVIII. POVERTY/ECONOMIC JUSTICE: Up to Poverty Campaign] (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - Massachusetts Law Reform Institute: Welfare Lobbying/Strategy Group 1992-98 (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - Massachusetts Welfare Rights Union 1998 (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - National Welfare Rights Union 1993, undated (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - National Organization for Women (NOW) Legal Defense and Education Fund 1997-98 (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - Pioneer Valley Welfare Rights Coalition: Holyoke outreach 1998, undated (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - Public Welfare Foundation: Welfare Reform Meeting 7-8 Apr 1997 (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - Unitarian Universalist Service Committee: Welfare and Human Rights Monitoring Project
      - General 1995-96, undated (Box 27, Folder 49)
      - Project reports 1996-98 (Box 27, Folder 50)
      - Human rights violation reports 1996, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Welfare Education Training Access Coalition (WETAC) 1996-2001, undated (Box 28, Folder 2-5)
    - Welfare Law Center 1996-99, undated (Box 28, Folder 6-7)
    - Welfare Mothers' Voice 1989-92 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Welfare Reform Response Team, Springfield 1998-99 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Welfare Warriors 1993, undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Women's Alliance 1998-99 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Working Family Agenda 1998-99, undated (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Reference files
    - Aid to Families with Dependent Children (AFDC)
      - General 1985-95, undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - "AFDC Advocacy Guide," Massachusetts Legal Reform Insitute Nov 1995 (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - "Changes to AFDC Program in Massachusetts," Coalition for Basic Human Needs Jun 1995 (Box 28, Folder 15)
      - Children's Clothing Allowance 1985-93, undated (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Emergency Assistance (EA) and Chapter 707 Rental Assistance Program (707), [see also SERIES XII. HOUSING and SERIES XI. HOMELESSNESS]
      - General 1985-95, undated (Box 28, Folder 17-20)
      - Survey for "Women in Transition" undated (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Emergency Assistance to Elderly, Disabled, and Children (EAEDC)
      - General 1993-99 (Box 28, Folder 22)
      - "EAEDC Advocacy Guide," Massachusetts Law Reform Institute Sep 1994 (Box 28, Folder 23)
      - Training 1995 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - General Relief (GR)
      - General 1990-91, undated (Box 28, Folder 25)
      - Training 1990 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Supplemental Security Income (SSI)
      - General 1990-95, undated (Box 28, Folder 27)
      - SSI Aware Training Jul 1991 (Box 28, Folder 28)
      - Basic Benefits Training circa 1996 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Transitional Assistance to Families with Dependent Children (TAFDC)
      - General 1995-99, undated (Box 28, Folder 30-31)
      - Advocacy Guide, Massachusetts Law Reform Institute 1996 (Box 28, Folder 32)
      - Facing Time Limits interviews 1998 (Box 28, Folder 33)
      - Time Limit petitions undated (Box 28, Folder 34)
      - Time Limits Training, Western Mass. Legal Services Oct 1998 (Box 28, Folder 35)
      - Time Limits Training undated (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) 1997-99 (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - Welfare fraud 1990, 1995, undated (Box 28, Folder 38)
    - Workfare/MassJobs 1991-97, undated (Box 28, Folder 39-41)
  - Reference file 1988-2001, undated (Box 28, Folder 42-44)
- SERIES XXV. PHOTOGRAPHS AND MEMORABILIA
  - Photographs undated (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
  - Memorabilia 1993, undated (Box 29, Folder 3-4)
- RESTRICTED MATERIALS
  Researchers must sign an access agreement form
  - SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION
    - Staff: grievances/incidents 1992, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - SERIES II. FINANCIAL
    - Donors 1987-99, undated (Box 30, Folder 2-4)
  - SERIES III. CHILDREN AND YOUTH
    - DSS Advocacy case files [CONFIDENTIAL] 1985-98, undated (Box 30, Folder 5-60)
  - SERIES IV. CRIMINAL JUSTICE
    - Community service
      - Attendance 1998-2006 (Box 30, Folder 61-64)
      - Individuals (Box 30, Folder 65-69)
  - SERIES VIII. FOOD AND HUNGER
    - Hot Meals 1987-88 (Box 30, Folder 70)
    - Referrals
      - Love Center 1988-90 (Box 30, Folder 71-73)
      - Open Pantry (Box 30, Folder 74-78)
      - Salvation Army 1988-90 (Box 30, Folder 79)
  - SERIES X. HIV/AIDS PREVENTION AND EDUCATION
    - Women in Support of Each Other (WISE): staff 1999-2000 (Box 30, Folder 80)
  - SERIES XI. HOMELESSNESS
    - Homeless Action Center phone log/intake forms 1987-89 (Box 31, Folder 1-14)
    - Phone line questionnaire 1990 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - SERIES XVI. PEER SUPPORT
    - Advocacy intake forms 1985-2005, undated (Box 31, Folder 16-23)
    - Referrals 1991-93, undated (Box 31, Folder 24-26)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION: Wall calendar with appointments and dates 1994, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - SERIES IV. CRIMINAL JUSTICE: Drawings, n.d.; poster for Political Prisoner Conference, n.d.; issues of Mass Rail publication of the Massachusetts Revolutionary Anti-Imperialist League (RAIL) 1995-98 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - SERIES VIII. FOOD AND HUNGER: Food Coop signs (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - SERIES IX. HEALTH CARE: UHCAN fan (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - SERIES XII. HOUSING: Rainville Hotel architects' Progress Prints for meeting 9 Sep 1992; poster for "No Housing No Peace" popular assembly coordinated by the October 6th Coaltion, n.d.; issues of Housing Matters, published by the Massachusetts Legal Reform Institute, 1989-93; winter 1990 issue of The Mass Tenant, published by the Massachusetts Tenants Resource Center and the MTO1989-93 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - SERIES XIV. JOBS AND LABOR: Feb 1979 issue of New Unity, Springfield, MA1979 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - SERIES XVII. POLITICAL PARTICIPATION: maps and statistics re Springfield mayoral and council races, after the Nov 2001 election (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - SERIES XVIII. POVERTY/ECONOMIC JUSTICE: Economic Human Rights Campaign posters 1998 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - SERIES XXI. SPRINGFIELD AND PIONEER VALLEY: copies of Springfield publications The Springfield Inquirer, 1994-97; la nueva era, 1994-98; the New Contract, Jul-Aug 1996; Springfield and Pioneer Valley Voice, 2000-021994-2002 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - SERIES XXIV. WELFARE: Clippings, 1997-98; issues of Welfare Mothers Voice, 1994-95 1994-98 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - SERIES XXI. SPRINGFIELD AND PIONEER VALLEY: Layout materials for Pioneer Valley Voice 2002 (Box 32, Folder 11)